LUIZ CLARO

Full Stack Flutter Developer

Ifclaro@gmail.com (647) 878 0194 Toronto, ON

luizclaro.com linkedin.com/in/luiz-claro github.com/LFClaro

About Me

I'm a versatile and creative developer. With a distinctive viewpoint to my projects, I design solutions with a user-oriented approach. Using my expertise in cross-platform full-stack development, I aim to play a role in improving user experiences.

My passion and commitment to continuous improvement make me a valuable asset to any team.

Relevant Work Experience



Full Stack Flutter Developer - God's Cleaning Crew

MAY 2023 - PRESENT

Tools: FlutterFlow, Flutter, Firebase/GCP, Node.js, Algolia, Stripe, GitHub, Jira, Jekyll

- Single-handedly developing and releasing three Flutter cross-platform MVPs (iOS, Android and web), using
 Flutter and the FlutterFlow low-code platform. The apps integrate with Firestore and Google Cloud
 Functions written in Node.js to handle client relations and job operations, while speeding up quote
 generation and service payment process.
 - The Admin app is a general business logistics manager that allows creation of new jobs, clients and workers in the company's database. Other features include Algolia search and quote generation with a fully implemented Stripe payment system for cards and direct bank debit;
 - The Clients app takes job requests directly, providing quotes and accepting payments via Stripe API;
 - The Workers app is an onboarding and management tool for service providers to receive new jobs and to get paid for their services, all via Stripe Connect API. They're also able to communicate via chat / Zego Cloud video call with clients;
- Maintaining the company's static website (created in Jekyll) via SSH and Git.
- Wrote a ChatGPT Blog Post automator script in Python which allows the company to create a full Jekyll blog post with text, image and HTML code / YAML front matter in less than 2 minutes, resulting in a 90% reduction in manual workload.



iOS Developer - TorontoJobs.ca | App Store

JAN 2022 - MAY 2022

Tools: Swift, SwiftUI, Adobe XD, CoreData, REST API integration, Jira, Azure Repos (Git)

- Conducted the development team on the **iOS** version of "*Guhuza*", a service that offers the ability for Employers & Job Seekers to complete the entire seeking / interviewing process on their platform.
- Created the wireframe for the UI on Adobe XD according to employer specifications and feedback.
- Implemented **Twilio** video chat function for the app.
- Wrote about 50% of the codebase by myself for the app's MVP.



Machine Learning Research Assistant/Team Supervisor - Humber College/Mitsubishi *MAY 2021 - SEP 2022*

Tools: Python, Pandas, SciKit Learn, GitHub

- Developed a function to train a Machine Learning model in **Python** to predict aircraft maintenance codes based on text analysis, which **improved prediction accuracy up to 91%**. This function also proved to be a **time-saver tool**, reducing errors and streamlining the model training steps.
- Led weekly team meetings between the Humber team and the Mitsubishi team, reporting advances and keeping track of information distribution.
- Trained a new wave of Research Assistants into the project.

Main Projects



Rental Service MERN Stack Web App | Github: <u>Server</u> & <u>Client</u> | <u>Live App</u> 2022

 An e-Commerce Web App focused on users renting and providing rent for daily use objects like electronics and tools. Using React.js, Node.js, Express.js and MongoDB.



Board Game Collection iOS SwiftUI App - "Shelfie" | <u>Github</u> 2022

 An app for board game collectors to get information on games by taking a photo of the physical boxes. Using Adobe XD, SwiftUI, CoreData, Firebase, and REST API integration.

Personal Projects

- Canada Newcomers Android App (2021)
 - Java, Firebase, API integration
- Board Game eCommerce Web App (2021)
 - C#, ASP.NET Core MVC, MySQL
- Toronto Foodie Laravel Web App (2020)
 - o PHP, Laravel, MySQL

Technical Skills

- JavaScript / TypeScript
- MERN Stack, Laravel, SpringBoot, ASP.NET
- REST API Development
- Python
- Flutter / Dart
- Swift (UIKit / SwiftUI)
- Android Java / Kotlin
- Java / J2EE
- Firebase / MongoDB, Oracle SQL / MySQL
- Git

Core Skills

- Excellent Communication
- Proactiveness
- Eagerness to Constantly Learn
- Teamwork
- Team leading
- Creativity
- Improvisation
- Project Management
- Documentation

Certification

• Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Education History



IT Solutions Postgraduate Program

Humber College - with Honours (GPA 3.9 / 4.0) SEP 2020 – MAY 2022

 Course load focused on Mobile / Web App Development and Database Development, with emphasis on SQL, Java, JavaScript, C#, PHP, HTML, CSS and Swift.



Bachelor in Film

Estacio de Sa University 2004-2008